# MONICA KAY PROVENCE

### • Full-Stack Software Developer •

I am a creative, detail-oriented person with a passion for intuitive, user-focused design. After almost a decade working as an Art Educator, Creative Entrepreneur, and Healthcare Advocate, I became interested in software development. I enrolled in a self-guided Python course through Udemy, and quickly realized that software development was the perfect combination of creative and strategic problem solving.

**Q** 615-656-3541

hey@monicakay.dev

heymonicakay.github.io
heymonicakay

# EDUCATION

Nashville Software School Full-Stack Development 2021

Coursera JavaScript Animation 2020 for Websites, Data Visualization, and Games

CSS Animated 2020 Components with ReactJS

Udemy 2020 UX Design: User Behavior & Psychology

Python Bootcamp 2019

> Middle Tennessee State University

B.S. Art Education 2016

## TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

#### Nashville Software School

Full-Stack Software Developer

Fully Remote 2020

Intensive six-month, full-time software development bootcamp with immersive, lab-based learning in Full-Stack Development, with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, SQL, and Python.

- 100% remote, simulated work-based learning environment
- Emphasis on team-based development
- Experience with Scrum process and agile workflow
- Used Git & GitHub for version control
- Experience in a full-time remote environment

#### Languages & Technologies

- HTML 5, CSS3, JavaScript, React,
- · JSON Server, SQL, Python, & Django
- Git & GitHub
- Visual Studio Code
- · Sketchboard, Miro, Figma, & dbdiabram
- · Canva, Vectornator, Concepts, & Bazaart

## COMMUNITY

Nashville JavaScript Attend monthly meetups and actively participate in group discussions.

Code For Nashville Attend monthly meetups and actively collaborate with other developers to solve social issues through innovative development.

> PyNash Attend monthly meetups and actively participate in group discussions.

Women In Technology of Tennessee

> Attend monthly meetups and actively participate in group discussions.

> > freeCodeCamp

Attend weekly meetups to practice algorithms and data-structure coding skills with other developers.

# PROJECTS

#### Neighborly

Server-Side Capstone

tinyurl.com/heyneighbor

Full-stack peer-to-peer commodity sharing application for environmentally conscious consumers, built with waste reduction in mind.

- Full CRUD functionality for complex relational data.
- Conducted User Research to inform development process.

#### Rare

Publishing Platform

tinyurl.com/mediamoguls (7)

Full-stack social application using a React client and Python-Django server, built 100% remotely by a team of six over the course of three Agile-Scrum sprints.

- Initiated team discussion about recurring workflow issues.
- Researched and presented possible solutions.
- Implemented changes, significantly reducing production roadblocks.

#### Wide Retriever

Client-Side Capstone

tinyurl.com/wideretriever

Dashboard application built with React where Dog Parents can set exercise and training goals for their dogs and track their progress.

- Full CRUD functionality for many-to-many data relationships
- · Utilized Miro and dbdiagram for planning
- Implemented JSON Server to store and return data
- Used CSS, Vectornator, and Canva for design

# SKILLS

Interpersonal Skills Time Management Public Speaking Team Building Remote Work Conflict Resolution Project Planning

### INTERESTS

Performing Improv Comedy Directing Sketch Comedy Writing Haikus International Travel Experimental Mixology Painting Oil Portraits Reading Walking My Dog

### AWARDS

"The Orator"

Nashville Software School For being able to cheer up my teammates and resolve conflicts smoothly,

"The Tomb Raider" Nashville Software School For digging up as much documentation as possible on new technologies.

> "The Burrito" Nashville Software School For being a positive force in the Cohort.

"Continuing Education Award" Kemberton For outstanding work in account resolution after only two months on the job.

## EXPERIENCE

#### Kemberton

Denials Specialist

Franklin, TN 2017 - 2020

Healthcare Company specializing in Patient and Provider advocacy through complex claims resolution.

- Wrote legal appeals on behalf of healthcare Providers & Patients.
- Played key role in resolving all high-dollar, complex accounts.
- Identified repetitive tasks, and wrote macros to automate them.
- Minimized opportunities for human error by building and distributing appeal templates to my teammates.
- Conducted daily research on current insurance policies.

### Technologies Used

- Teams, Office 360, OneNote, Planner, Access, Excel, Word
- EPIC Systems

Licensee/Artist

#### Paint Nite

Nashville, TN & Memphis, TN 2014 - 2019

The premier "social painting" company in the U.S.

- Started as a Teaching Artist and took over operations for the Nashville Market in 2017.
- Grew Private Event revenue for the Nashville Market from roughly \$10,000 annually to over \$70,000 in my first year.
- Launched Paint Nite Memphis in 2018, and developed selfsustaining team remotely from home in Nashville, TN.

#### Technologies Used

- Facebook Ads, Hootsuite, Instagram Ads
- GSuite
- · Canva, Photoshop, InDesign

### Firstlight Arts Academy

Art Teacher

Brentwood, TN 2013 - 2016

Artist training studio for students age four to adult.

- Contributed to comprehensive curricula for all ages.
- Identified individual student's learning needs and modified teaching style accordingly.

### VOLUNTEER

#### Disaster Relief

Tornado Relief Coordinator

Nashville, TN March 2020

- Worked closely with Hands On Nashville to dispatch teams to locations where volunteers were needed.
- Assisted with manual labor and cleanup.

Covid-19 Essentials Distributer

April - July 2020

 Packaged and delivered essential products to elderly and immunocompromised Nashville Residents during pandemic.

#### Kids Arts Festival

Franklin, TN 2015 - 2016

Volunteer Event Coordinator

- Coordinated execution of a community mural, painted by hundreds of participants during the festival.
- Oversaw activities of volunteers and art booths on site.
- Curated student art gallery with over 500 works of art.